<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>inversion | Xiaolong Wei</title><link>https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/tag/inversion/</link><atom:link href="https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/tag/inversion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>inversion</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>inversion</title><link>https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/tag/inversion/</link></image><item><title>Geometry inversion and uncertainty quantification</title><link>https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/project/geometry_inversion_and_uncertainty_quantification/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/project/geometry_inversion_and_uncertainty_quantification/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="figure-caption">Figure Caption&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>The recovered 2D SEG-EAGE salt models without (a) and with (b) constraint. The reconstructed Sigsbee salt models without (c) and with (d) constraint.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We developed an efficient 3D trans-dimensional Monte Carlo framework for reconstructing the spatial geometry of an anomalous body using gravity data. The proposed framework can also quantify the uncertainty of the shape of an anomalous body recovered from geophysical measurements.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Probabilistic geology differentiation</title><link>https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/project/probabilistic_geology_differentiation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/project/probabilistic_geology_differentiation/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="figure-caption">Figure Caption&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>(Top) The probabilities of spatial distribution for Units 2 to 9. Warmer colors represent higher probabilities, and colder colors indicate lower probabilities. (Bottom) The probabilities of geological units at different locations indicated by black boxes.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="https://sites.google.com/view/jiajiasun/research/geology-differentiation" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Geology differentiation&lt;/a> takes geophysical measurements and inversion results one step closer to the goal of characterizing subsurface geology. It provides a natural way to incorporate prior geological knowledge, physical property measurements and the inverted physical property models into one framework, and helps us to extract more information from geophysical data sets. The results of geology differentiation are typically in the form of a 3D quasi-geology model which shows the spatial distribution of various geological units identified during the geology differentiation process. It is, therefore, of practical significance to be able to quantify the uncertainties of the geological units in a quasi-geology model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We have developed an effective workflow to construct 3D probabilistic quasi-geology models in the deterministic inversion framework. Two essential components of our workflow are the generation of a large sequence of equivalent physical property models and the acceptance/rejection of these models. We have used mixed Lp norm joint inversion to generate a large sequence of density contrast and susceptibility models. The prior physical property measurements on drill core samples have been used to accept only these models that are consistent with physical property measurements. We have performed geology differentiation for all these accepted models and obtained a set of 3D quasi-geology models, based on which we quantify uncertainties of spatial distributions for each geological unit and calculate probabilities of geological unit types at any location in a study area.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Uncertainty analysis of potential field data inversion</title><link>https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/project/uncertainty_analysis_of_potential_field_data_inversion/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/project/uncertainty_analysis_of_potential_field_data_inversion/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="figure-caption">Figure Caption&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A set of recovered density models range from a wide spectrum of model features with the depth slices at -2000 m (upper) and cross sections at 4790800 m (lower). We note that these models contain the consistent level of data fitting. The diverse model characteristics reveal the uncertainties of gravity gradient inversions.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="research-summary">Research Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>We have developed an empirical method to quantify the uncertainties of the inverted models in the 3D deterministic inversion framework. We have employed the mixed Lp norm inversion, a very recently developed inversion method, which allows different norms to be applied to the four different components of the regularization term. Our work shows that the uncertainties of the 3D inverted models can be empirically assessed in the deterministic framework by taking advantage of the adjustable parameters. We emphasize that a better practice for interpreting field data sets is to create a large sequence of equivalent yet diverse models and factor the uncertainties into interpretations, instead of basing his or her interpretation on a single &amp;ldquo;optimal&amp;rdquo; model.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>3D undercover structure of Precambrian intrusion</title><link>https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/project/3d_undercover_structure_of_precambrian_intrusion/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://xiaolongw1223.github.io/project/3d_undercover_structure_of_precambrian_intrusion/</guid><description>&lt;h3 id="figure-caption">Figure Caption&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>A 3D view of the newly identified geological units based on joint inversion results.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="project-summary">Project Summary&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>Mineral exploration under a thick sedimentary cover naturally relies on geophysical methods. We have used high-resolution airborne magnetic and gravity gradient data over northeast Iowa to characterize the geology of the concealed Precambrian rocks and evaluate the prospectivity of mineral deposits. We performed separate and joint inversions of magnetic and gravity gradient data to obtain 3D density contrast models and 3D susceptibility models, based on which we carried out geology differentiation. we identified 10 geologic units and their spatial distributions in 3D based on separately inverted physical property values. The extension of 2D geologic interpretation to 3D allows for the discovery of four previously unidentified geologic units, a more detailed classification of the Yavapai country rock, and the identification of the highly anomalous core of the mafic intrusions. Joint inversion allows for the classification of a few geologic units further into several subclasses.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>